<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Poetry, Fiction, Magick and Musings</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Notes Toward a System of 'Punk Magick'</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing I haven’t talked about much on this blog is my spirituality. I was raised Catholic, but I didn’t stay that way. I bounced around a lot of different religious currents before settling under the neopagan umbrella and specifically becoming a Heathen. I started out primarily worshipping Odin, then Freya, and now I’m beginning to work with Loki. I practice magick as well, divining using runestones, creating runic talismans, and using meditation and pathworking to commune with the Gods. But the way I go about it is a bit different than most.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 20:45:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /punk-magick-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/punk-magick-notes</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Occult Library Co-Op</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;“I don’t get it,” said Arkham, as they weaved their way through the shelves. “Libraries don’t usually restrict access. ‘Information belongs to the public’ and all that, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 20:00:37 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /the-occult-library-co-op</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-occult-library-co-op</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Support the Author</title>
        
          <description>&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2020/08/Penclaw-Press-Banner_BK.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;The Penclaw Press Text Logo&quot; srcset=&quot;/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/Penclaw-Press-Banner_BK.png 600w, /content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/Penclaw-Press-Banner_BK.png 1000w, /content/images/2020/08/Penclaw-Press-Banner_BK.png 1500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 15:23:57 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /support-the-author</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/support-the-author</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Poem: Busted Seams</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m brimming and bursting,&lt;br /&gt;
my seams are busted.&lt;br /&gt;
My righteous sense of reality&lt;br /&gt;
is rusted.&lt;br /&gt;
“Fact or fiction,”&lt;br /&gt;
a fallacy.&lt;br /&gt;
There is no ordered truth,&lt;br /&gt;
objectively.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 20:58:18 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /busted-seams</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/busted-seams</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Poem: A Knight Of Verse</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The pen and the sword are weapons both,&lt;br /&gt;
and whichever I wield, let thie be my oath:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 20:16:26 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /poem-a-knight-of-verse</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/poem-a-knight-of-verse</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Poem: Dragon of Avalon</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Dragon,&lt;br /&gt;
fire-breating,&lt;br /&gt;
rage-seething&lt;br /&gt;
protector.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 19:49:14 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /dragon-of-avalon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/dragon-of-avalon</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Poem: Lonely Little Robot</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Little robot, rusting alone,&lt;br /&gt;
resting on the grass,&lt;br /&gt;
how corroded your chromium has become,&lt;br /&gt;
how green your copper plating.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 22:13:18 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /lonely-little-robot</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/lonely-little-robot</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Romance on the Asexual Spectrum</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I broke up with my first boyfriend because he wanted to have sex eventually and I didn’t. I was definitely attracted to him. I loved kissing him, holding him, dancing with him, cuddling him. I just didn’t want to fuck him. I enjoyed, to a certain extent, the dirty talk we did over text messages and the like. But when things started to get too heavy, I got uncomfortable real quick, and was unable to reciprocate. I had considered the fact that I was on the asexual spectrum before, but I didn’t think I was on it because of the strong feelings I had for my boyfriend. I had read about the differences between romantic and sexual attraction before, but I had a hard time telling the two apart. I don’t have that trouble anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 17:39:37 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /romance-on-the-asexual-spectrum</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/romance-on-the-asexual-spectrum</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Poem: The Wall Bisecting</title>
        
          <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wall-bisecting&quot;&gt;The Wall, Bisecting&lt;/h2&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 20:43:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /members-only-poem-the-wall-bisecting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/members-only-poem-the-wall-bisecting</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Smattering Of Poetry</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Poetry has been something that I have been interested in ever since school. I love reading it, and I love to write it even more. My style varies wildly. Sometimes I like to use a more formal format like a villanelle, other times I use free verse. Recently, I have experimented with adding alliteration for my amusement. Poetry lets me play with the sound and music of the world of words. Its a wonderful, beautiful experiment in twisting the threads of language into a long, beautiful cord. And it can be an incredibly cathartic thing as well, allowing me to express feelings that would otherwise be hard to get across.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 19:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a-smattering-of-poetry</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a-smattering-of-poetry</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Science-Fiction Writer's Argument Against Futuristic Meritocracy</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I see someone ask the question of “what will we use as money in the future,” I’m always tempted to respond “who says we’ll even have money?” Its not inconceivable to me that the world we live in will change drastically in a century’s time or even less. We may think that money based economies will still exist, but the truth is that we have no way of knowing. Take someone from the early 1900s and show them the life we are living now and it would be completely incomprehensible to them.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 22:22:06 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a-science-fiction-writers-argument-against-futuristic-meritocracy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a-science-fiction-writers-argument-against-futuristic-meritocracy</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Non-Exhaustive List of Science Fiction Tropes to Avoid</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, science fiction. Whether gritty or corny, dystopian or utopian, it has an ability to entrance like no other genre of speculative fiction. At least most of the time. Well, some of the time. Well…ninety percent of anything is crap, right? Anyway here’s a bunch of tropes that annoy me in science fiction stories. It’s by no means exhaustive, nor is it a bible to follow religiously, but it is a point of reference I think I should have if I want to write good science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 19:22:57 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a-non-exhaustive-list-of-science-fiction-tropes-to-avoid</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a-non-exhaustive-list-of-science-fiction-tropes-to-avoid</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A DnD Character Appreciation Post for Vix, The Badass Anime Furry</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a lot of DnD characters over the years. Some of them have been more self-indulgent than others. Some of them have been simple experiments with the rules, or with classes and races that I haven’t played before. But my current character is probably one of the most self-indulgent things I have ever made. Everyone, meet Vix, the fox-shifter spore druid.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:12:10 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a-dnd-character-appreciation-post-for-vix-the-badass-anime-furry</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a-dnd-character-appreciation-post-for-vix-the-badass-anime-furry</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>About Alex</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Alex Penclaw is a blogger and writer of speculative fiction. She particularly loves writing science fiction and horror. She is also a hobbyist sysadmin working on setting up her own Mastodon server. When not writing on this blog, they can often be found posting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://efdn.club/@xandra&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 15:59:32 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /about-alex</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/about-alex</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
