<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-19T18:48:26-05:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">The Penclaw Press</title><subtitle>Poetry, Fiction, Magick and Musings</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Notes Toward a System of ‘Punk Magick’</title><link href="/punk-magick-notes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notes Toward a System of 'Punk Magick'" /><published>2020-08-24T20:45:42-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-24T20:45:42-04:00</updated><id>/punk-magick-notes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/punk-magick-notes">&lt;p&gt;One thing I haven’t talked about much on this blog is my spirituality. I was raised Catholic, but I didn’t stay that way. I bounced around a lot of different religious currents before settling under the neopagan umbrella and specifically becoming a Heathen. I started out primarily worshipping Odin, then Freya, and now I’m beginning to work with Loki. I practice magick as well, divining using runestones, creating runic talismans, and using meditation and pathworking to commune with the Gods. But the way I go about it is a bit different than most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a witch, and a heathen, but a very different kind of witch and heathen. I write bindrunes and sigils on popsicle sticks with gel pens to make talismans. I use led candles so as not to start a fire accidentally while meditating. And speaking of meditating, one of the ways I induce “gnosis” is by putting on my headphones and listening to some dark ambient electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an assumption that magick is old and that it comes from the “natural world.” But the truth is that you don’t have to be naked under the moonlight in a peaceful glade to do anything magickally related. And the “natural world” is a misnomer, anyway, because nature is all around us, even in massive urban centers. From the pigeons pooping on the sidewalk to the cockroaches scurrying through your pantry, the so-called “natural world” is constantly intruding on our so-called “civilization.” Likewise, magick can be found all around us. You don’t need to leave to seek it out, its already here. Just open your mind to the possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practicing magick has lead to a better understanding of myself and my place in the universe. It has alos lead to more self-confidence, and a feeling of being in control of my own destiny. I want to share those feelings with others, and I don’t just mean the green neo-hippie crowd. I want everyone to have access to magick that works for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-punk-magick&quot;&gt;What is ‘Punk Magick’?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me be clear here: Punk is not simly an aesthetic. As the Dead Kennedys say (in the aptly titled “Nazi Punks Fuck Off”), you ain’t hardcore if you spike your hair when a jock still lives inside your head. Punk is about raging against the constraints that bind you. Its about rejecting conventional authority, or really all authority, and striving for true autonomy. But it is not individualist, either. Real punks practice radical compassion and empathy and seek to make their communities a better place. They know that it is all of us against The Man for the good of everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Punk Magick is magick by the people and for the people, no matter where they are. It takes many forms, but it is as much about the goals of using magick as the techniques and style of practice. Like alchemists trying to turn lead into gold, punk mages try to change the world around them into something that smells less like shit. They use magic to help their community and resist their oppressors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what Punk Magick is, in a nutshell:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Punk Magick is transformative.&lt;/strong&gt; The point of magick is to transform yourself and your surroundings. It helps you reclaim agency when you feel stuck. It helps you know yourself when you feel lost. It is not omnipotent, but it is a transformative tool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Punk Magic is diverse and accessible.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t need to be descended from a witch burned at Salem to master magick. You &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; don’t need any overpriced crap from an exploitative online retailer. Magick doesn’t care about the color of your skin, your gender(s) or lack thereof, your sexual identity, whether your able bodied or neurotypical, or even what religion you are. Anybody can do it. All you need is belief and will.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Punk Magick is intersectional.&lt;/strong&gt; Punk mages practice radical empathy and care about their communities. They’re not just philosophically against racism, sexism, ableism, heteronormativity and the like - they actively oppose those forces whenever and however they can. There is no freedom until &lt;em&gt;all of us&lt;/em&gt; are free.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Punk Magick is antifascist.&lt;/strong&gt; There is nothing “Punk” about white supremacy in any of its modern incarnations. There is nothing “Punk” about letting the government get away with atrocities. Punk mages ally themselves against fascist movements and engage in active resistance if possible. (Diversity of tactics plays a role here - not everyone can attend a protest or throw a milkshake at a fascist).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Punk Magick is anti-dogmatic.&lt;/strong&gt; Arguing about what kind of things are and are not “real” magick is not Punk. If it works for someone and isn’t appropriative or otherwise harmful to the oppressed, leave it be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Punk Magick is creative.&lt;/strong&gt; By all means, read whatever magical treatise and grimoires you connect with, but trust your inventiveness. Experiment. Try new things. Sow sigils on patches. Make runestones from discarded bottle caps. Create a shrine to a deity that didn’t exist until you thought them up. Magick is not a dusty old thing. Magick is creativity and will given form in the universe.
&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that in no place have I descirbed a formal system of magick. Formal systems constrain and lead to dogmatism and infighting. I have, unfortunately, learned this lesson the hard way. So I’m hoping that I can paint a way forward for any potential mage regardless of their particular style. Consider this as being similar to “Chaos Magick,” except more politically oriented and hopefully more inclusive. (By the way, the flag at the top of the post is free to use, without attribution).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect that as my magickal practice continues to evolve that I will write more about my experiments and discoveries. I may even publish a grimoire at some point. In any case, this feels like a starting point towards a wider journey. I hope you will join me on it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="magick" /><summary type="html">One thing I haven’t talked about much on this blog is my spirituality. I was raised Catholic, but I didn’t stay that way. I bounced around a lot of different religious currents before settling under the neopagan umbrella and specifically becoming a Heathen. I started out primarily worshipping Odin, then Freya, and now I’m beginning to work with Loki. I practice magick as well, divining using runestones, creating runic talismans, and using meditation and pathworking to commune with the Gods. But the way I go about it is a bit different than most.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Occult Library Co-Op</title><link href="/the-occult-library-co-op" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Occult Library Co-Op" /><published>2020-08-13T20:00:37-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T20:00:37-04:00</updated><id>/the-occult-library-co-op</id><content type="html" xml:base="/the-occult-library-co-op">&lt;p&gt;“I don’t get it,” said Arkham, as they weaved their way through the shelves. “Libraries don’t usually restrict access. ‘Information belongs to the public’ and all that, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serafin just smiled. “For ordinary libraries, this is true. But we are no ordinary library.” She ran her fingers over a row of books. “These books must be treated with care, and only used by responsible people. The knowledge they contain is quite dangerous. Hence why members must be approved beforehand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But they’re books,” said Arkham. “Just ink and paper. Sure, they may have spells and things in them, but that doesn’t make them dangerous.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You really think so?” said Serafin, plucking a book of the shelf and handing it to Arkham. “Then here you go. Read away.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Begrudgingly, Arkham took the book and turned to the first page. They instantly regretted doing so. A wave of information crashed on thier head. Letters, numbers and symbols, seemed to dance around them mockingly, defying all logic yet driven by some infernal mechanism known only to them. It felt like they were surrounded by a vortex of pure data, and were being dragged out of their body and stright down into an abyss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They awoke on the floor, panting and shivering. The book was beside them, closed neatly on the floor. Serafin stood above them, looking down. Her face was young, but her eyes were old and tired, and Arkham could see the faintest glimmer of disappointment in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, young Arkham,” said Serafin. “I suppose know you see what I was getting at, yes?” Arkham nodded feebly, and Serafin helped them up off the floor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="fiction" /><summary type="html">“I don’t get it,” said Arkham, as they weaved their way through the shelves. “Libraries don’t usually restrict access. ‘Information belongs to the public’ and all that, right?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Support the Author</title><link href="/support-the-author" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Support the Author" /><published>2020-08-13T15:23:57-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-13T15:23:57-04:00</updated><id>/support-the-author</id><content type="html" xml:base="/support-the-author">&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2020/08/Penclaw-Press-Banner_BK.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;The Penclaw Press Text Logo&quot; srcset=&quot;/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/Penclaw-Press-Banner_BK.png 600w, /content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/Penclaw-Press-Banner_BK.png 1000w, /content/images/2020/08/Penclaw-Press-Banner_BK.png 1500w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you like the things that I do? Do you like the poetry I write, or my blog posts? Would you like to see some exclusive poetry and microfiction? Do you have a crush on me? Ha ha, just kidding. Unless….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any of the above things are true, consider subscribing to this blog. For just $5.00 USD a month or $50.00 USD a year, you can get access to member exclusive content, such as poetry and a Monthly Microfic Mashup based around a particular theme. I’m also looking into creating member exclusive surveys about the type of content I produce in order to have amore tailored member experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any of these things appeal to you, please do not hesitate to &lt;a href=&quot;/signup/&quot;&gt;subscribe!&lt;/a&gt;You’ll be helping me tremendously by doing so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poem: Busted Seams</title><link href="/busted-seams" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poem: Busted Seams" /><published>2020-08-12T20:58:18-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T20:58:18-04:00</updated><id>/busted-seams</id><content type="html" xml:base="/busted-seams">&lt;p&gt;I’m brimming and bursting,&lt;br /&gt;
my seams are busted.&lt;br /&gt;
My righteous sense of reality&lt;br /&gt;
is rusted.&lt;br /&gt;
“Fact or fiction,”&lt;br /&gt;
a fallacy.&lt;br /&gt;
There is no ordered truth,&lt;br /&gt;
objectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggle and strain &lt;br /&gt;
to straighten out&lt;br /&gt;
the delusions and disappointments&lt;br /&gt;
that make me doubt&lt;br /&gt;
my mind and motive.&lt;br /&gt;
I meditate&lt;br /&gt;
on sense and sensorium&lt;br /&gt;
to satiate &lt;br /&gt;
heuristic hunger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I wonder&lt;br /&gt;
what witchly powers womanhood brings&lt;br /&gt;
to make me doubt the manly things&lt;br /&gt;
and float above on feminine wings.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="poetry" /><category term="gender" /><summary type="html">I’m brimming and bursting, my seams are busted. My righteous sense of reality is rusted. “Fact or fiction,” a fallacy. There is no ordered truth, objectively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poem: A Knight Of Verse</title><link href="/poem-a-knight-of-verse" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poem: A Knight Of Verse" /><published>2020-08-12T20:16:26-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T20:16:26-04:00</updated><id>/poem-a-knight-of-verse</id><content type="html" xml:base="/poem-a-knight-of-verse">&lt;p&gt;The pen and the sword are weapons both,&lt;br /&gt;
and whichever I wield, let thie be my oath:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To champion causes that are righteous and just,&lt;br /&gt;
but never to let my heart come to rust,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For compassion and love are the drives of the knight,&lt;br /&gt;
and it is these blessed feelings that fuel the fight.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html">The pen and the sword are weapons both, and whichever I wield, let thie be my oath:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poem: Dragon of Avalon</title><link href="/dragon-of-avalon" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poem: Dragon of Avalon" /><published>2020-08-12T19:49:14-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T19:49:14-04:00</updated><id>/dragon-of-avalon</id><content type="html" xml:base="/dragon-of-avalon">&lt;p&gt;Dragon,&lt;br /&gt;
fire-breating,&lt;br /&gt;
rage-seething&lt;br /&gt;
protector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let all of the world&lt;br /&gt;
be a holy treasure&lt;br /&gt;
to be shared and enjoyed&lt;br /&gt;
and never hoarded,&lt;br /&gt;
until the last of us here has boarded&lt;br /&gt;
the ship to Avalon&lt;br /&gt;
the world beyond&lt;br /&gt;
gaurded&lt;br /&gt;
by dragons.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html">Dragon, fire-breating, rage-seething protector.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poem: Lonely Little Robot</title><link href="/lonely-little-robot" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poem: Lonely Little Robot" /><published>2020-08-08T22:13:18-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-08T22:13:18-04:00</updated><id>/lonely-little-robot</id><content type="html" xml:base="/lonely-little-robot">&lt;p&gt;Little robot, rusting alone,&lt;br /&gt;
resting on the grass,&lt;br /&gt;
how corroded your chromium has become,&lt;br /&gt;
how green your copper plating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lonely robot, lying here,&lt;br /&gt;
how long you must have waited,&lt;br /&gt;
how solitary your station,&lt;br /&gt;
out here in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arise, spurned automaton&lt;br /&gt;
and no longer be alone.&lt;br /&gt;
Come be with comrades and compatriots&lt;br /&gt;
and know kindness, compassion and love.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html">Little robot, rusting alone, resting on the grass, how corroded your chromium has become, how green your copper plating.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Romance on the Asexual Spectrum</title><link href="/romance-on-the-asexual-spectrum" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Romance on the Asexual Spectrum" /><published>2020-08-08T17:39:37-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-08T17:39:37-04:00</updated><id>/romance-on-the-asexual-spectrum</id><content type="html" xml:base="/romance-on-the-asexual-spectrum">&lt;p&gt;I broke up with my first boyfriend because he wanted to have sex eventually and I didn’t. I was definitely attracted to him. I loved kissing him, holding him, dancing with him, cuddling him. I just didn’t want to fuck him. I enjoyed, to a certain extent, the dirty talk we did over text messages and the like. But when things started to get too heavy, I got uncomfortable real quick, and was unable to reciprocate. I had considered the fact that I was on the asexual spectrum before, but I didn’t think I was on it because of the strong feelings I had for my boyfriend. I had read about the differences between romantic and sexual attraction before, but I had a hard time telling the two apart. I don’t have that trouble anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in a long distance relationship currently. Me and my partner message each other each day to check in and see how the other is doing. We talk about whats going on in our lives and offer comfort to one another when things get tough. We send each other stickers and gifs of couples kissing and cuddling. We talk about how much we miss each other, though we’ve yet to meet in person, and how we would love to visit each other when it gets safer to travel. We are both on the asexual spectrum, and very much in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every so often I hear people say that they are “tired of romance.” They then go on to complain about struggling to meet people, about buying people expensive gifts and jewelry, about going on dates, and all those sorts of things. I don’t think of that as “romance.” I think of that as “courtship.” Courtship is how you go about meeting people who you are romantically and/or sexually interested in. Courtship differs between cultures and time periods. Romantic and sexual attraction is, as far as I can tell, part of how an individual is “wired,” so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to my sexual orientation, I often talk about my romantic orientation. I am panromantic, meaning that I can and often do get crushes on people of any gender. These romantic feelings often involve wanting to hold hands, kiss, cuddle and other such things, but they don’t involve sexual urges most of the time. This is what I think  of when I think of “romantic attraction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its worth pointing out here that there are people who do not feel romantic attraction just as there are people who do not feel sexual attraction. They don’t become attracted to people in the same way that others are. Whereas I often might form a romantic crush on someone after meeting them, an aromantic person would not have feelings of the same type or intensity. Sometimes these people are asexual, but not all the time. They exist, and their identity is valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this post because I’ve run into people who question the need for the notion of romantic orientation or romantic attraction. Whatever intentions the makers of such arguments have, they are contributing to the erasure of both the asexual and aromantic spectrums. We should not be so quick to question the need of a label that people identiy strongly with even if we ourselves do not understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author’s Note: The original post I made was very angry, and I ended up going for the simplest argument instead of the more accurate one. I have since updated my post to clarify what I mean by romantic attraction and how being panromantic differs from being pansexual or aromantic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="asexuality" /><summary type="html">I broke up with my first boyfriend because he wanted to have sex eventually and I didn’t. I was definitely attracted to him. I loved kissing him, holding him, dancing with him, cuddling him. I just didn’t want to fuck him. I enjoyed, to a certain extent, the dirty talk we did over text messages and the like. But when things started to get too heavy, I got uncomfortable real quick, and was unable to reciprocate. I had considered the fact that I was on the asexual spectrum before, but I didn’t think I was on it because of the strong feelings I had for my boyfriend. I had read about the differences between romantic and sexual attraction before, but I had a hard time telling the two apart. I don’t have that trouble anymore.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poem: The Wall Bisecting</title><link href="/members-only-poem-the-wall-bisecting" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poem: The Wall Bisecting" /><published>2020-08-02T20:43:56-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-02T20:43:56-04:00</updated><id>/members-only-poem-the-wall-bisecting</id><content type="html" xml:base="/members-only-poem-the-wall-bisecting">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wall-bisecting&quot;&gt;The Wall, Bisecting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone has been building a wall&lt;br /&gt;
down the center of the city. Pulleys&lt;br /&gt;
move bricks and tools up to the workers&lt;br /&gt;
on either side. I climbed&lt;br /&gt;
up the scaffolding, following the pulley&lt;br /&gt;
to a worker laying bricks.&lt;br /&gt;
I asked why he was building&lt;br /&gt;
the wall. He sighed, and said,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t know.” So I climbed back down&lt;br /&gt;
and packed my bag. At dawn, I left the city&lt;br /&gt;
by car, following the wall by way of the Westward&lt;br /&gt;
road alongside it. When I reached the edge of town&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the wall did not stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It continued down the highway, bisecting&lt;br /&gt;
towns and villages. And always there were worksers&lt;br /&gt;
on either side, building it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ceased following the wall when&lt;br /&gt;
I came to the coast and the road&lt;br /&gt;
stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wall didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is bisecting the sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html">The Wall, Bisecting</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Smattering Of Poetry</title><link href="/a-smattering-of-poetry" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Smattering Of Poetry" /><published>2020-08-02T19:54:02-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-02T19:54:02-04:00</updated><id>/a-smattering-of-poetry</id><content type="html" xml:base="/a-smattering-of-poetry">&lt;p&gt;Poetry has been something that I have been interested in ever since school. I love reading it, and I love to write it even more. My style varies wildly. Sometimes I like to use a more formal format like a villanelle, other times I use free verse. Recently, I have experimented with adding alliteration for my amusement. Poetry lets me play with the sound and music of the world of words. Its a wonderful, beautiful experiment in twisting the threads of language into a long, beautiful cord. And it can be an incredibly cathartic thing as well, allowing me to express feelings that would otherwise be hard to get across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few poems I recently sent in for a fellowship prize. I didn’t get chosen as a finalist, but I stand by the poems as works of art and a good example of the kind of writing I can do when I put my heart into my words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-lies-my-brain-hs-told-me&quot;&gt;The Lies My Brain Hs Told Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That I’m worthless,&lt;br /&gt;
a whiner,&lt;br /&gt;
that I am nothing,&lt;br /&gt;
nobody,&lt;br /&gt;
these are the lies my brain has told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That my work and words are pitiful,&lt;br /&gt;
worthless drivel,&lt;br /&gt;
that no one ever&lt;br /&gt;
enjoys them,&lt;br /&gt;
these are the lies my brain has told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That my politics are misguided,&lt;br /&gt;
that power thrives&lt;br /&gt;
and I, in my isolation&lt;br /&gt;
am impotent,&lt;br /&gt;
these are the lies my brain has told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That it would have been better&lt;br /&gt;
not to be a burden&lt;br /&gt;
and to relieve my parents&lt;br /&gt;
of my poverty,&lt;br /&gt;
these are the lies my brain has told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That nothing I do&lt;br /&gt;
will be of note&lt;br /&gt;
and I shall die unknown&lt;br /&gt;
and unloved,&lt;br /&gt;
these are the lies my brain has told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do not have to listen to them&lt;br /&gt;
anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eulogia-draconis&quot;&gt;Eulogia Draconis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pity the dragon that was slain&lt;br /&gt;
by a knight and cut in twain&lt;br /&gt;
for it was only acting by its nature,&lt;br /&gt;
at least according to its nomenclature:&lt;br /&gt;
drakkon, the serpent from the Earth,&lt;br /&gt;
which guards what the gods have deemed to be worth&lt;br /&gt;
more than a fool of noble birth.&lt;br /&gt;
So pity the dragon, for it knew better than I&lt;br /&gt;
which mortals should live and which should die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-glimpse-at-my-mind&quot;&gt;A Glimpse at My Mind&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thoughts are hidden, but my words&lt;br /&gt;
are wanton things.&lt;br /&gt;
They demand to be shared&lt;br /&gt;
and spred around.&lt;br /&gt;
To write is to publicize,&lt;br /&gt;
to publish oneself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think on my words,&lt;br /&gt;
and wearily&lt;br /&gt;
I realize that, together,&lt;br /&gt;
they tangle me&lt;br /&gt;
in a net of my own devising&lt;br /&gt;
that they have drawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my words may free me&lt;br /&gt;
from my fetters&lt;br /&gt;
if I only realize that the state&lt;br /&gt;
of sorrow&lt;br /&gt;
is but a temporary present, and not&lt;br /&gt;
a prophecy of tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;abjuration-against-gender&quot;&gt;Abjuration Against Gender&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goddess, God, and every deity&lt;br /&gt;
of the Earth, the Sky, and the mighty Sea,&lt;br /&gt;
to your power I now surrender.&lt;br /&gt;
Free me from this thing called gender!&lt;br /&gt;
Let me be like the great oak tree,&lt;br /&gt;
unconcerned with what humans see,&lt;br /&gt;
and from these shackles let me be free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;
&lt;!--kg-card-begin: markdown--&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;herbal-remedies&quot;&gt;Herbal Remedies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some St. John’s Wort to heal the cut,&lt;br /&gt;
some chamomile tea to soothe the gut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basil leaves and honey yo keep the cough at bay,&lt;br /&gt;
motherwort to send the headache on its way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A balm of juniper berries to aid with gout,&lt;br /&gt;
Some rose water to help the liver out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spearmint compress for the feverish head&lt;br /&gt;
Some lavender oil to sleep soundly in bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herbs have I for cuts, bruises, fever and chills;&lt;br /&gt;
nothing have I for society’s ills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--kg-card-end: markdown--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will likely post more poetry on this blog in the near future. Maybe I’ll even create chapbook of sorts to sell online. Anyway, I hope you enjoy my poetry, and I look forward to sharing more of it with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html">Poetry has been something that I have been interested in ever since school. I love reading it, and I love to write it even more. My style varies wildly. Sometimes I like to use a more formal format like a villanelle, other times I use free verse. Recently, I have experimented with adding alliteration for my amusement. Poetry lets me play with the sound and music of the world of words. Its a wonderful, beautiful experiment in twisting the threads of language into a long, beautiful cord. And it can be an incredibly cathartic thing as well, allowing me to express feelings that would otherwise be hard to get across.</summary></entry></feed>