<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/tag/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-11-19T18:38:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/tag/blog/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">The Penclaw Press | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Poetry, Fiction, Magick and Musings</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Romance on the Asexual Spectrum</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/romance-on-the-asexual-spectrum" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Romance on the Asexual Spectrum" />
      <published>2020-08-08T17:39:37-04:00</published>
      <updated>2020-08-08T17:39:37-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/romance-on-the-asexual-spectrum</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/romance-on-the-asexual-spectrum">&lt;p&gt;I broke up with my first boyfriend because he wanted to have sex eventually and I didn’t. I was definitely attracted to him. I loved kissing him, holding him, dancing with him, cuddling him. I just didn’t want to fuck him. I enjoyed, to a certain extent, the dirty talk we did over text messages and the like. But when things started to get too heavy, I got uncomfortable real quick, and was unable to reciprocate. I had considered the fact that I was on the asexual spectrum before, but I didn’t think I was on it because of the strong feelings I had for my boyfriend. I had read about the differences between romantic and sexual attraction before, but I had a hard time telling the two apart. I don’t have that trouble anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in a long distance relationship currently. Me and my partner message each other each day to check in and see how the other is doing. We talk about whats going on in our lives and offer comfort to one another when things get tough. We send each other stickers and gifs of couples kissing and cuddling. We talk about how much we miss each other, though we’ve yet to meet in person, and how we would love to visit each other when it gets safer to travel. We are both on the asexual spectrum, and very much in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every so often I hear people say that they are “tired of romance.” They then go on to complain about struggling to meet people, about buying people expensive gifts and jewelry, about going on dates, and all those sorts of things. I don’t think of that as “romance.” I think of that as “courtship.” Courtship is how you go about meeting people who you are romantically and/or sexually interested in. Courtship differs between cultures and time periods. Romantic and sexual attraction is, as far as I can tell, part of how an individual is “wired,” so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to my sexual orientation, I often talk about my romantic orientation. I am panromantic, meaning that I can and often do get crushes on people of any gender. These romantic feelings often involve wanting to hold hands, kiss, cuddle and other such things, but they don’t involve sexual urges most of the time. This is what I think  of when I think of “romantic attraction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its worth pointing out here that there are people who do not feel romantic attraction just as there are people who do not feel sexual attraction. They don’t become attracted to people in the same way that others are. Whereas I often might form a romantic crush on someone after meeting them, an aromantic person would not have feelings of the same type or intensity. Sometimes these people are asexual, but not all the time. They exist, and their identity is valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this post because I’ve run into people who question the need for the notion of romantic orientation or romantic attraction. Whatever intentions the makers of such arguments have, they are contributing to the erasure of both the asexual and aromantic spectrums. We should not be so quick to question the need of a label that people identiy strongly with even if we ourselves do not understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author’s Note: The original post I made was very angry, and I ended up going for the simplest argument instead of the more accurate one. I have since updated my post to clarify what I mean by romantic attraction and how being panromantic differs from being pansexual or aromantic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="blog" />
      
        <category term="asexuality" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I broke up with my first boyfriend because he wanted to have sex eventually and I didn’t. I was definitely attracted to him. I loved kissing him, holding him, dancing with him, cuddling him. I just didn’t want to fuck him. I enjoyed, to a certain extent, the dirty talk we did over text messages and the like. But when things started to get too heavy, I got uncomfortable real quick, and was unable to reciprocate. I had considered the fact that I was on the asexual spectrum before, but I didn’t think I was on it because of the strong feelings I had for my boyfriend. I had read about the differences between romantic and sexual attraction before, but I had a hard time telling the two apart. I don’t have that trouble anymore.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A Science-Fiction Writer’s Argument Against Futuristic Meritocracy</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/a-science-fiction-writers-argument-against-futuristic-meritocracy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Science-Fiction Writer's Argument Against Futuristic Meritocracy" />
      <published>2020-08-01T22:22:06-04:00</published>
      <updated>2020-08-01T22:22:06-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/a-science-fiction-writers-argument-against-futuristic-meritocracy</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/a-science-fiction-writers-argument-against-futuristic-meritocracy">&lt;p&gt;Whenever I see someone ask the question of “what will we use as money in the future,” I’m always tempted to respond “who says we’ll even have money?” Its not inconceivable to me that the world we live in will change drastically in a century’s time or even less. We may think that money based economies will still exist, but the truth is that we have no way of knowing. Take someone from the early 1900s and show them the life we are living now and it would be completely incomprehensible to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science fiction writers know this quite well, and love to experiment with alternative economies and futuristic ways of ending the scarcity of resources. However, a good number of them never think to question the fundamental necessity of things like a meritocratic society. They often magic scarcity away bit leave much of how society is today intact, as though once peoples basic needs are met there will still be  need to restrict access to “luxuries.” The reputation economy trope is perhaps the biggest offender here, exchanging physical capital for social capital, slapping a utopian setting on top of it, and calling it “the solution to capitalism.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me be very clear here: I hate meritocratic societies with a fiery burning passion. I have lived all my life in meritocratic institutions. I grew up in a extremely competitive “blue ribbon” school district in a middle-class suburb. I was an honors student and my GPA was either a 4.0 or higher since middle school. I went to a fancy private college and graduated with a high GPA. Then I got fired from my entry-level job for essentially not working fast enough, and began the slow decline to where I am now: a twenty-nine year old adult living with their parents because they got a “useless” BA in English. There are people who would say this is my fault, that I should not have chosen such a field as English, that I should hve gone into a STEM field or been a Computer Science major. I hear those people’s voices in my head a lot when my chronic depression hits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A meritocratic society gives you all the credit when you succeed and puts the responsibility square on your shoulders when you fail. I had a lot of priviliges other people don’t get to have: a good education, a middle class suburban upbringing, and parents who are willing to support me even when the only job I’ve been able to hold on to is a part-time job as a page in the local public library system. If I didn’t have those things, especially the support of my parents, I might very well be houseless right now. Yet these priviliges are erased in the meritocratic philosophy that runs our society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the conditions leading up to my subsequent under-employment are erased and I just get assumed to be lazy. It doesn’t matter that I hated my entry-level job and was depressed for a long time, or that I couldn’t wrap my head around advanced code, or that despite both of my parents teaching the subject I couldn’t do college-level calculus to save my life. It doesn’t matter that there are days when I have to fight to even be able to get out of bed let alone get work done. It doesn’t matter that, when all these factors were combined, I just wan’t able to output the massive amount of crunch required as a software tester. No, its entirely my fault that I am now financially dependent on my parents, who themselves are not doing the best financially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any society that is meritocratic will have these issues. When your society gives all the credit to the individual whent hey succeed, it ignores the priviliges that helped them to do so. When your society places all the blame on the individual when they fail, it disencentivizes people to help the struggling and the downtrodden, because it was “their fault” that they got to be in those circumstances. In short, when you have a meritocratic society, no matter what it uses instead of money, you are just having capitalism 2.0. And I think that science fiction should try to be a bit more imaginative than that.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="blog" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Whenever I see someone ask the question of “what will we use as money in the future,” I’m always tempted to respond “who says we’ll even have money?” Its not inconceivable to me that the world we live in will change drastically in a century’s time or even less. We may think that money based economies will still exist, but the truth is that we have no way of knowing. Take someone from the early 1900s and show them the life we are living now and it would be completely incomprehensible to them.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">A DnD Character Appreciation Post for Vix, The Badass Anime Furry</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/a-dnd-character-appreciation-post-for-vix-the-badass-anime-furry" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A DnD Character Appreciation Post for Vix, The Badass Anime Furry" />
      <published>2020-07-30T20:12:10-04:00</published>
      <updated>2020-07-30T20:12:10-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/a-dnd-character-appreciation-post-for-vix-the-badass-anime-furry</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/a-dnd-character-appreciation-post-for-vix-the-badass-anime-furry">&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a lot of DnD characters over the years. Some of them have been more self-indulgent than others. Some of them have been simple experiments with the rules, or with classes and races that I haven’t played before. But my current character is probably one of the most self-indulgent things I have ever made. Everyone, meet Vix, the fox-shifter spore druid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vix is a shifter who lives on the continent of Thoria. She is a Druid by training, and until very recently lived with her enclave, the Enclave of the Mycorex, in a secluded grove in the middle of an untamed wilderness bustling with magical creatures. She is able to morph from her standard anime-girl form to a full on anthropomorphic fox, as well as take on the forms of various other animals that she’s seen. She’s also a spore druid, and is constantly surrounded by fungal spores which she can “activate” in order to gain a boost to her HP and deal extra damage in melee. Spore druids are also talented at necromancy, and Vix is only one level away from raising the dead. In short, she’s a goth furry anime girl and basically the person I wanted to be for a lot of my college years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vix has been able to hold her own in the party quite well. She’s passed just enough survival checks to annoy the heck out of the DM, who was hoping for a more difficult jaunt through the wilderness. She is both the party’s main source of in-combat healing and tied with the rogue for most monsters killed. Her signature weapon is the “Moonbeam” spell, which has lead to more than one “Sailor Moon” reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not everything has been sunshine and roses for her. The second session of the campaign saw her possessed by a cursed staff which forced her to destory much of her home village. She was rescued by the party, but fears that she may never be able to return to her village ever again. This has made her interesting to play, as the last session saw the party visiting another grove during a massive celebration. A celebration that she would’ve normally spent with her own grove. It was interesting to roleplay her interactions with the members of this other grove. It was equal parts melancholly and bittersweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DnD is collaborative storytelling, but its also a chance to put on a costume of sorts and become someone different. Sometimes a character gets stuck in your head, and captures your heart, and keeps you going between sessions. That’s a type of magic as powerful as any seventh level spell.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="blog" />
      
        <category term="dnd" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I’ve had a lot of DnD characters over the years. Some of them have been more self-indulgent than others. Some of them have been simple experiments with the rules, or with classes and races that I haven’t played before. But my current character is probably one of the most self-indulgent things I have ever made. Everyone, meet Vix, the fox-shifter spore druid.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
